RAHUL MONDAL

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

CONTACT

+91 8777036966 rrmondal12@gmail.com portfolio-website

SKILLS

Rust (Actix, Axum, Yew,
Tauri)
JS (Node, React)
Python (TensorFlow)

MongoDB, PostgreSQL

Kubernetes, **Docker**, Okteto,

WebRTC, WebSocket, JWT, ProtoBuf, gRPC, Hashing, Encryption, Asym-Cryptography

EDUCATION

Future Institute of Tech.

2017-2021

Computer Science &

Engineering

Sonarpur Sikhsa Sadan 2015-2017 Higher Secondary (XII)

Harinavi D. V. A. S. High School **2014-2015** Secondary (X)

PROFILE

Aspiring and versatile software artisan with a flair for AI and over 3 year of experience. Eagerly pursuing a riveting software development role where creativity meats innovation, to craft cutting-edge solutions and contribute to transformative projects.

EXPERIENCE

Full-Stack Web Developer (Rust)

Freelance | Mar. 2024 - Present

- Engineered an 'Exchange-Engine' (using Rust & WebSockets), on a special client request, to facilitate real-time transaction between buyers and sellers.
- Reduced search time for matching buyers and sellers by ~80% through a simple solution (utilizing Hashmaps).

Software Developer (RUST)

Digital Aptech Pvt. Ltd. | Oct.2023 - Mar.2024

- Single-handedly developed a chat-widget end-to-end using Yew.rs with technologies like WebSocket & WebRTC to enable Real-time communication, improving UX and accessibility.
- Successfully migrated multiple microservices from Warp to Axum, optimizing
 performance and scalability, and implemented thorough over 100 test cases
 for enhanced code reliability and automated testing.
- Leveraged **Docker** and **Kubernetes** for seamless container orchestration, deploying applications using **Helm** charts, resulting in improved scalability and reliability.
- Implemented CI/CD pipelines with Okteto, streamlining development workflows and accelerating code delivery by ~30%.
- Collaborated closely with the client and a three-person team to build a reliable product, assisting in developing a microservice utilizing **gRPC** to establish **WebSocket channels**.

Software Developer (Rust)

Rapid Innovation | Jan.2022 - Sept.2023

- Developed a desktop app with Rust (Tauri, Actix-Web) to monitor remote employees, enhancing productivity.
- Utilized **MongoDB**, and vanilla.js, later integrating **React.js** for the web version, now supporting over 200+ remote employees.
- Increased employee productivity by ~20% through continuous feedback, real-time monitoring, and streamlined performance tracking.